He took someone else's idea and America ate it up.
The Founder is a drama, history film directed by John Lee Hancock.
The true story of how Ray Kroc, a salesman from Illinois, met Mac and Dick McDonald,
who were running a burger operation in 1950s Southern California.
Kroc was impressed by the brothers’ speedy system of
making the food and saw franchise potential.
He maneuvered himself into a position to be able to pull the company
from the brothers and create a billion-dollar empire.
Ray Kroc, played by Michael Keaton.
Dick McDonald, played by Nick Offerman.
Mac McDonald, played by John Carroll Lynch.
Joan Smith, played by Linda Cardellini.
Harry J. Sonneborn, played by B. J. Novak.
Ethel Kroc, played by Laura Dern.
The Founder is a 2016 biographical drama film directed by
John Lee Hancock and written by Robert Siegel.
Starring Michael Keaton as businessman Ray Kroc, the film depicts the story of his creation of the McDonald's fast-food restaurant
chain, which eventually involved forcing out the company's founders to take control with conniving ruthlessness.
Nick Offerman and John Carroll Lynch co-star as McDonald's founders Richard and Maurice
McDonald, alongside Linda Cardellini as Ray Kroc's third wife Joan Smith, and B.
Novak as McDonald's president and chief executive Harry J.
The film premiered at Arclight Hollywood on December 7, 2016, and was released
theatrically in the United States on January 20, 2017, by the Weinstein Company.
It grossed $24 million worldwide and received generally positive reviews from
critics, who praised the performances of Keaton and Offerman.
The film explores themes of greed, ambition, biography,
family business , based on true story.
The tone is emotional.